

ZAHEER AHMED

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER COMPUTER SCIENTIST

CONTACT



+92 3351443176



zaheercena@gmail.com

HOUSE NO 240, BLOCK 29, JAUHARABAD, PUNJAB PAKISTAN

INDEPENDENT RESEARCHER

Subject: Cryptography

Institution: Self Taught(Multiple)

Influencers: Dr.Dan Boneh

Prof. Cristof Paar



+923451187489



/zaheercena



/zaheercena



/zaheercena

LANGUAGES

English Native

Urdu Mother Tongue

Punjabi Native Spanish Beginner Hindi Can Speak

SUMMARY

As a Computer Scientist I Love Computer Security. I Developed Two Operating Systems in C++ and D Lang. From 2010 I am attached to Electronics Systems and Computer Science (Software/Hardware).

I worked as Software Developer and Systems, IT Engineer and also Electronics Engineer. I once owned a Lab for Electronics Research.

EXPERIENCE

IT ENGINEER

MAC ESTATE & BUILDERS | JAN 2017 - PRESENT

• I am Responsible for Maintaining Systems of MAC Estate Software/Hardware, Database and Social Media.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

DNSPAK PVT | JULY 2015 - DEC 2016

• I used to Develop Android Applications like Hybrid and Native Applications and used API's (Google, Twitter, Youtube, Maps),

ELECTRONICS ENGINEER

FUTURE INTERNET | OCT 2010 - MAR 2011

• I worked as Electronics Engineer during the time and worked on various Systems.



EDUCATION

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF THE PUNJAB | 2011 - 2015 LAHORE PAKISTAN

DAE ELECTRONICS ENGINEER ASSOCIATE

SARGODHA POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE | 2007 - 2010 JAUHARABAD PAKISTAN

HYDROPONIC SYSTEMS

PMAS UAAR | 2017 **ISLAMABAD PAKISTAN**

SKILLS

- Computer Security
- Android Development
- C++/Java Development
- Operating Systems
- Software Requirement Specification
- OS Development
- Cryptography/Cryptoanalysis
- P2P Networking
- Systems Network Engineering
- Electronics Manufacturing
- System Support

INTERESTS

- Android Development
- Security Algorithms
- Theoretical Physics
- Cryptology
- Learning New Languages
 Time Dilation (Spanish)
- Embedded Programming
- Electronics Systems
- String Theory(Physics)
- Critical Thinking